Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: December 10, 2015
MARY: I'm going
to tell you a story
about a boy
who would never grow up,
about the pirate
who wished to kill him,
about the island
where fairies roamed.
But this isn't the story
you've heard before,
because sometimes
friends begin as enemies,
and enemies begin as friends.
Sometimes to truly understand
how things end,
we must first know
how they begin.
(PANTING)
(PEOPLE LAUGHING)
WOMAN: Come on.
(BABY GURGLES)
(GASPING)
I love you, my son.
I love you,
my Peter.
(KISSES)
- (RINGING)
- SISTER JOSEPH: Wakey, wakey!
Rise and shine!
Come on, now.
That's it. Come on.
Move along.
Come on, quickly now.
Peter, we'll miss breakfast.
(BOYS WHOOPING)
The heroes have risen.
They must now feed!
SISTER JOSEPH:
Quiet over there!
I said quiet!
Eat that up! Now.
- I won't tell you again!
- (CANE STRIKING)
(GRUNTS)
Where's the bacon?
We always have bacon rind
of a weekend.
There's a war on, Peter.
Rationing.
You're lucky to have
any food at all.
Oh! Mother Barnabas,
forgive me.
Get over there.
How much you wanna bet
she's nickin' all the rations?
Shh. She'll hear ya.
She's got ears
like an elephant.
- Bum like one, too.
- (BOTH LAUGHS)
Look.
More empty seats.
Nelson and Billy
both got evacuated.
Lucky sods.
Both of them?
- When?
- Don't know.
When I woke up,
they were both gone.
Off to some family in Canada
until the war's over.
I wouldn't mind goin' there.
Don't be daft.
You gotta stay put.
For when our mums
come fetch us?
Exactly.
We hunker down here.
Hold the fort.
Wait for the cavalry.
(SIGHS)
Now, get on that roof and
clean those filthy gutters.
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
PETER: Is it safe,
Mother Barnabas?
Well, I've not
tested it meself, like.
You know, not recently.
But all the necessary
paperwork is in order
should an orphan
perish in a fall.
Now get up there!
And while you're aloft
and closer to our Lord,
you may reflect on
your festering souls.
Your souls that fester
as do the leaves.
See! I was right!
She's hoarding
all the rations.
Where's she hiding
all the grub?
Her office.
No one's ever been in there.
I heard a rumor
it's booby trapped.
SISTER JOSEPH:
Silence, I said! Quiet!
(AIR-RAID SIREN WAILING)
(PANICKED YELLING)
Everyone,
down to the shelters!
In chaos is death!
(DOOR CREAKING)
- Come on.
- I don't like this.
Fort Knox.
- The lair of the dragon.
- (MISSILE WHISTLING)
Whoa!
Come here.
So put your hands there.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
I need your shoe, fella.
- Could you just...
- NIBS: Quiet!
Right.
Nineteen.
Twenty.
(INHALES SHARPLY) Peter.
Ugh. What a dirty old nun.
(SNIFFS) Ugh.
(BLOWS)
NIBS: This is so unhygienic.
Why is the Virgin Mary
so clean?
(NIBS YELPS)
- Nibs?
- Down here!
Nibsy!
I told ya.
Booby trapped.
(DISTANT EXPLOSIONS)
PETER: It's a treasure trove.
NIBS: Flippin' heck!
(COINS CLINKING)
(LAUGHS)
Peter!
It's the records.
It's your file.
Is it from your mum?
What does she say?
PETER: I can't.
Will you read it?
- I meant aloud.
- Oh.
"My dearest Peter.
"Everything I have done,
"I have done
because I love you.
"I long for the day that
I can come back for you
"and explain everything.
"Don't doubt me
"nor most importantly,
"don't doubt yourself.
"You are extraordinary."
NIBS AND MARY:
"More than you can imagine."
MARY: I promise that
you will see me again,
in this world or another.
- (EXPLOSION)
- Come on!
(MISSILE WHISTLING)
That's my private property!
Give it back!
You know, Peter, every little
orphan dreams he's special.
That he'll be the one
whose mother comes
a-skipping back for him.
But your mammy's
not for skipping.
And why is that, hmm?
Because you're not special,
Peter.
- (GRUNTS)
- You're not even special
in your own way.
You're just
a nasty little creature
abandoned by a feckless mammy
who's forgotten you exist.
- (YELLING)
- (GASPS)
Oh! You little savage!
- (BANGS TABLE)
- Hands! The both of ya!
He never did nothin'!
He's guilty by association.
It is time
for the pine.
Oi, Skinny.
Arnold and the twins,
when did they go?
Me guess it were last night.
All the missing children,
all that dough
hidden in her office.
What's Barnabas up to?
She's selling orphans.
I knew it!
I mean, is she?
That's not nice.
But who in the world
buys orphans at night?
That's what
we have to find out.
Now, come on,
let's make a plan. It'll be fun.
NIBS: I've heard
that one before.
(BOYS SNORING)
(BOY FARTS)
(SNIFFING)
Cor! Who guffed one?
Nibsy!
I never.
(GROANS)
Mmm-mmm. Mmm-mmm.
(PETER HUMMING)
(SIGHS)
This was a stupid plan.
I'm going back to bed.
- Come on.
- (GROANS)
(BOYS CONTINUE SNORING)
- Night.
(TOY WHINING)
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
(BOY YELLS)
- Nibs!
- NIBS: Peter!
(PIRATE LAUGHING EVILLY)
PETER: I told you
it would happen tonight.
I was right!
What? (YELPS)
(LAUGHING CONTINUES)
(BOYS SCREAMING)
Head for the stairs.
- Go!
- (EXHALES SHARPLY)
- Nibs!
- (NIBS YELLING)
Goodbye, Peter!
(PETER GRUNTS)
- You're comin' with me!
- Let go!
(PETER SCREAMING)
- (LAUGHING)
- Peter.
Holy pudding!
Prepare to set sail!
(PIRATES SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
NIBS: We've gotta
get out of here.
We'll have to jump.
I can't!
NIBS: We have to!
Come on!
Nibs!
(SCREAMING)
And away we go!
- (BISHOP LAUGHING)
- Come on!
Friends till death!
Peter!
Damnation.
You've sunk my frigate.
Ma'am. Luftwaffe. Inbound.
Ladies.
Sector 6, sector 8, sector 12.
FERNLEY: Incoming!
Spitfire!
- FERNLEY: Clear the deck!
- PIRATE: Ready your swords!
Oh, come on!
Ma'am, regarding identification
of the enemy, um, aircraft,
it rather resembles a, um...
Spit it out, man.
It looks like a pirate ship, ma'am.
Come again?
PIRATE: Fire!
(IMITATING AIRPLANE)
(IMITATING MACHINE GUN FIRE)
Whoa!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GRUNTING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHIMPERS)
(BLOWING)
(GRUNTING)
(BISHOP GRUNTING)
- (GROANS)
- (WHIMPERS)
Get off.
Don't go dying.
You're precious cargo.
- Am I?
- Somebody thinks so.
- Is it my mother?
- (LAUGHING)
(PIRATES SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
Going up!
(GASPING)
(SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
(AIRPLANE ENGINES SPUTTERING)
(CHUCKLES)
(GASPS)
Whoa.
(YELPS)
(GROANING)
(GASPS)
PIRATE: Get out here!
You little rat!
Make your move!
Come on, hurry up!
Move it! Come on!
PIRATE #1: Right this ship
for docking.
PIRATE #2: Haul away!
Come on, fellas.
ORPHAN #1: Look! It's daylight.
ORPHAN #2: I wanna see this!
- ORPHAN #1: What is that?
- ORPHAN #2: Move, I can't see.
MINE WORKERS: (SINGING)
♪ Hello, hello, hello, how low? ♪
Is this Canada?
ALL: (SINGING)
♪ Turn the lights out ♪
♪ It's less dangerous ♪
♪ Here we are now ♪
♪ Entertain us ♪
♪ I feel stupid ♪
♪ And contagious ♪
♪ Here we are now ♪
♪ Entertain us ♪
♪ Hey! ♪
♪ Hello, hello, hello, how low? ♪
Sing!
Kneel!
I don't kneel to anyone.
Oh, you'll kneel to him.
He's the pirate
all pirates fear!
The original nightmare!
The man they call Blackbeard!
ALL: (SINGING)
♪ And I forget just why I taste ♪
♪ Oh, yeah, I guess
it makes me smile ♪
♪ I found it hard,
so hard to find ♪
♪ Oh, well, whatever, never mind ♪
♪ Hello, hello, hello, how low? ♪
(BLACKBEARD LAUGHING)
♪ With the lights out ♪
♪ It's less dangerous ♪
♪ Here we are now ♪
♪ Entertain us ♪
♪ I feel stupid and contagious ♪
Sing for your master!
♪ Here we are now ♪
♪ Entertain us ♪
(MINE WORKERS YELLING)
Sweet, gentle children.
You who weep molten pearls
of innocent tears,
dry them, dear nippers.
For I have sprung you
from life's cruel dungeon,
and hereby grant you liberty!
(ALL CHEERING)
Suffer no more.
Come unto me. You are home.
(ALL CHEERING)
Here you join orphans alike
from every corner
of the globe,
every race, creed, and color.
Every age and era.
You are pioneers.
Brave creators
of a new society.
For this,
my poppets,
is a land of opportunity!
(ALL CHEERING)
My justice is divine.
My laws are so simple
you could write them
on a pig's ear.
In fact, I have.
(LAUGHING)
Law number one,
"Those who work
with bright, honest vigor
"will be rewarded with prizes
"and trophies
"and confectionery!"
(ALL CHEERING)
Law number two,
"Those who fail to work hard,
"those who skive or malinger,
"will hereby know the brooding
majesty of my disapproval."
(SPRAYING)
Mark me well.
I know no pity.
(CHUCKLING) No second chances.
I don't do mercy.
But remember,
don't forget
to help yourselves
to lots and lots
of jolly old fun!
(LAUGHING)
Hey, kiddiewinks,
welcome to Neverland!
(INDISTINCT CONVERSATIONS)
SILVERMAN:
Put some effort into it.
You better find me some Pixum!
- Harder! Work harder!
- (BOYS GRUNTING)
Uh, Sam Smiegel, supervisor.
No, thank you. Take it off.
- Whoa!
- Excuse me.
What are we digging for?
(SCOFFS)
Did no one explain?
We are mining
for these little chaps.
Fairy dust,
otherwise known as Pixum.
Fairies are real?
Mmm. They were real, yeah.
There were millions of them
all over the island.
What happened to 'em?
Oh, Blackbeard hunted them
into extinction.
- Why?
- For the fairy dust.
You know, the old Pixum.
What does he want it for?
I don't have no idea.
No one knows. No one's
allowed to know. (LAUGHING)
Well, you best not
dwell on it. Just...
SILVERMAN:
Get a move on!
Real, actual fairies.
HOOK: Hey, new kid,
you just got here
on a flying pirate ship.
"Real" should be a very fluid
concept for you right now.
Get to diggin'. (GRUNTS)
Give me your pick, kid.
Your hand's all messed up
because your blade is blunted.
If you keep
swingin' like that,
you're gonna break your wrist.
I'm Peter.
How long have you been here?
(SIGHS)
Forever.
Do you know why they want it
so badly? The Pixum?
You ask too many questions, kid.
They kill for it.
We die for it. End of story.
- Thanks very much.
- Don't thank me.
I don't care about you.
I'm not your friend,
and I haven't got your back.
Simple as that.
Shoo, kid.
(GRUNTING)
(GASPS)
PETER: Fairy dust.
- (GASPS)
- I found some.
That's mine!
No!
ROBBINS: I found some!
PETER: Oi, thief! I found it!
(GROANS)
Oi, small fry, button it.
Move!
(GASPING)
Give it to me.
It was me!
I found the fairy Pixum!
This bogey stole it.
SILVERMAN:
He said he found it.
That means he found it. Clear?
Clear as the scar
on your ugly face!
(ALL GASPS)
- (LAUGHS)
- SILVERMAN: Take him
to the Captain!
Disorder and verbals.
Move out of the way. Move it.
Get out of the way!
There... There is a procedure
for this, you know.
You're not supposed to...
- Shut it, Mr. Clipboard.
- Oh!
Let's see
what Blackbeard makes
of this nasty little thief.
Oh, what you lookin' at?
I was tryin' my best.
Well, go on, then.
Back to work. Thank you.
Did you find
the natives' camp?
They found us, sir.
They sprang from the trees
and laid waste to
40 of our most formidable men.
Then they disappeared
back into the forest
as if they were never there.
- Whoa. Whoa. Whoa.
- We will get them, Captain.
Given the proper time.
Time?
Mmm.
I have sucked these mines dry.
There's almost nothing left.
I must have their lands.
But these savages
continue to ambush my ships,
operating from
some hidden camp,
which no one can seem to find.
And yet you assure me all will
be well given the proper time.
There is no time! None!
Oh...
Excuse me, Captain.
(SIGHS)
Hey ho. (CHUCKLES)
The show must go on.
How do the miners seem?
Dirty, feverish,
on the brink of collapse, sir.
Why must it be so hard?
(SIGHS)
So...
Who are we making
an example of today?
MINERS: (SINGING)
♪ Hey ho, let's go! ♪
♪ They're forming
in a straight line ♪
(BOY WHIMPERING)
♪ They're going through
a tight wind ♪
No, no!
What's going on?
What do you think? (LAUGHS)
♪ They're piling in the backseat ♪
♪ They're generating steam heat ♪
♪ Pulsating to the backbeat ♪
♪ The Blitzkrieg Bop ♪
Any clearer now?
(CONTINUES LAUGHING)
♪ Hey ho, let's go! ♪
- (ALL CHEERING)
- BLACKBEARD: Yeah!
Brave heroes of Neverland,
behold these traitors.
I entrust their fate
to your gracious whim.
This barbarian...
(WHISPERS) ...caught
stealing from the grain store.
...was caught squealing
from the grain store.
Stealing.
- Stealing.
- Twice.
Twice!
(ALL BOOING)
- Will you spare him?
- ALL: No!
Or do you lust for justice?
ALL: Justice!
- SMEE: Yes!
- MINERS: Justice!
- Do they ever have mercy?
- Oh, yes. They do.
Often?
Uh...
Let's go!
Don't answer that.
(PETER GASPS)
This boy has been
in our mines but one day
and has already proven himself
to be a thief,
a rabble rouser,
and a Pixum fraudster.
- I never!
- BLACKBEARD: I ask,
shall you have mercy
for the willful child?
ALL: No!
Or do ye be nasty?
ALL: Nasty!
(CHANTING)
Nasty! Nasty! Nasty!
BLACKBEARD: Alack.
The people have spoken.
Think a happy thought.
(PETER SCREAMING)
(GASPING)
(MINERS MURMURING)
(PETER WHOOPS)
(WHOOPING JOYFULLY)
I'll be darned.
I don't believe it! I can fly!
- (THUDS)
- (PETER GROANS)
(GASPS)
BLACKBEARD:
Neverland is a dream
From which you never wake.
Ever had that one?
A dreadful nightmare
you know is not real,
but your sleep is so heavy,
so deep, so delicious
that you just can't wake up.
Drowning in sleep.
Slow dream
drowning in
the soft, black sea.
Do you know that sea, Peter?
It's death, boy.
Murmuring to you.
It's where we end.
Most of us.
Would you like some chocolate?
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
Childhood ain't so jolly.
In fact, it's rather frightening.
Agree?
(PETER BREATHING SHAKILY)
Are you brave, Peter?
(STAMMERS) I try to be.
Yes, of course.
Are you scared?
Yes.
Have you ever flown before?
No.
(EXHALES SHARPLY)
Beyond that wall,
there are savage people.
They have an ancient prophecy
from when the fairy kingdoms
reigned on this island.
The prophecy tells of a boy
born of the love
between a fairy prince
and a human girl.
A boy who would be
disappeared from this world
until he was old enough
to return and lead
an uprising against me.
A boy, so says the prophecy,
who could fly.
Have you come to kill me, Peter?
I don't believe
in bedtime stories.
PETER: "Me... Me.
"Huh... Eh...
"Er..."
MARY: I promise that
you will see me again,
in this world or another.
"Or another."
(DOOR OPENS)
Go on! Get in there!
(DOOR SLAMS)
PETER: "Or another."
(GASPS)
- HOOK: Hey, flyboy.
- Yeah?
That was some little airshow
you put on out there.
Could you do that again?
Who wants to know?
(GRUNTS)
Of course I can fly.
You saw me.
Hmm.
Good.
Put your ear
to that wall over there.
(TICKING)
Now that's the sound
of a blast cap
I stuck to the other side.
Set to go off in 30 seconds.
If I fly, you'll help me
find my mother?
I reckon she's here
on the island.
It's not a negotiation, kid.
Without me,
you're stuck in this cell.
you're stuck in these mines.
Okay, then
we'll talk about it.
Just move away from that wall
before you get yourself
blown up, all right?
- So, what's it gonna be?
- Kid!
Tick
tock.
Okay, we have a deal, just...
(GASPS)
Flyboy?
Hurry! Slide down.
They'll be comin' for us.
If I'm gonna trust you,
I need to know your name.
It's Hook.
The name's James Hook.
- Happy?
- No!
(HOOK YELLING)
Left foot
in front of the other,
put the right one
in front of the other.
That's it. It's called walking.
Off you go. Go on.
HOOK: Smee.
Well, go on, then. Carry on.
- HOOK: Smee. Down here!
- Whoa.
- HOOK: Six o'clock.
- (GROANS)
I don't... Yes...
HOOK: Darn it, Smee,
in the basket.
(EXCLAIMS IN SHOCK)
Please don't call me Smee.
Smee, can you get me
to the surface?
(WHISPERING)
There is no use.
Once you're up there,
you can't get anywhere else.
Not today.
(GASPS)
(GRUNTING)
(PANTING)
Good knowing ya.
You've been a true friend.
Someday I'll find a way
to repay you.
Now, send us up.
(DOOR CLOSES)
What the heck?
You just said someday
you'll find a way to repay me.
Someday, not today. Get out!
SMEE: I think that's
a very minor technicality.
Someday could be today,
if you think about it.
- And, moreover...
- HOOK: Smee!
SMEE: Yes.
HOOK: That's where we're headed.
The Skyport.
We can take one of
the cable cars up to the dock.
Then you'll fly us to a ship.
Okay?
- (GROANS)
- Huh?
(LAUGHS)
(MEN SCREAMING)
Keep your head down, kid.
(MAN SCREAMS)
(MAN GROANS)
Go! Go!
(CABLE CAR BELL DINGS)
See? They anchor the galleons
far enough off the dock,
so they're impossible
to steal.
So you want me to fly from the
dock, over to one of the...
What? Speak now,
or forever hold your peace.
(ALL GASPS)
SMEE: Are we meant
to have stopped?
PETER: Whoa.
Heave! Heave!
Forget the Skyport.
You have to do it now.
Are you waiting
for a formal invitation?
- Go! Now!
- I'm afraid of heights!
What? You can fly!
Yesterday was my first time.
Well, you better fly again,
or we're all gonna fall
for the last time.
Might we bicker
about this later?
Smee! The sword!
Yeah, that's gonna work, kid.
Get up there
and wave it at 'em.
(GRUNTING)
PIRATE: Heave!
(PANTS)
(PETER SCREAMING)
- (WHOOPING)
- (SCREAMING)
(GRUNTS)
- (METAL CREAKING)
- (SCREAMS)
That was close.
Do you know
how to work a ship?
HOOK: How hard could it be?
- Smee! The rope!
- Yes! Yes!
- Clear!
- HOOK: Boy!
HOOK: Whoa!
This is a lot harder
than it looks! (GRUNTING)
Yeah! We're sailin' now!
Well, do you have
anything to say?
(GROANS) I worked really hard
setting up that table.
What? Forget the table.
Pick them up later.
If that boy makes it
to the natives,
you can forget any chance
of us winning this war.
All will be lost.
We'll find them, sir.
They can't have gone far.
- Well, then where are they?
- (RUMBLING)
(ALL LAUGH MOCKINGLY)
Get me that boy
before the savages do!
(YELPS)
- Dead ahead!
- (GASPS)
(GRUNTS)
Ahhh!
HOOK: Smee! Get off my leg!
(SCREAMS)
(PIRATES SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
SMEE: I think I'm gonna be sick!
The wall! The wall!
Somebody, please help me!
Turn! (GRUNTS)
(PETER SCREAMING)
Smee! Get the sails up!
We need a strong headwind
to make the jump!
What jump?
Home! We're gettin'
the heck off this island!
No-ho!
You said we'd find my mother!
I'm not leaving Neverland!
(CREAKING)
Well, not now, anyway!
SMEE: Get the sails up!
The sails!
This is gonna be
a little rough!
Put the sails up!
(ALL SCREAMING)
(LIQUID HISSING)
(SNIFFING)
(BREATHING DEEPLY)
(EXHALES)
(KNOCKING ON DOOR)
How many times...
I am not to be disturbed
when I'm at the Rejuvenator!
Yes?
I am sorry, Captain,
but it's about the boy.
Mmm-hmm?
The stolen ship went down
in the Neverwood.
So the boy is lost?
Yes, sir. He is a lost boy.
But our best men
are searching for him now.
I am surrounded by imbeciles.
Must I do everything myself?
Sir, you can't really believe
that this pipsqueak
is the one.
He hardly seems capable.
His mother
hardly seemed capable either,
and yet, here we are.
PETER: The deal was
to help me find my mother.
You were gonna break it.
That's very wrong.
HOOK: No, you broke the
deal first. You lied to us.
No, I fibbed. I can fly.
Just not every day.
- (CREAKING)
- Whoa!
(WHIMPERING)
(GROANS) Our only way
off this island
and now it's in pieces.
Satisfied?
Well, yes. I'm quite content.
'Cause I don't wanna
get off this island.
HOOK: All the years that I've
wasted planning to get out.
All gone.
Hey! Quit messing around.
It's not safe in here.
PETER: Every ship has one.
A what?
PETER: A map.
What does that say?
"Tribal Territory."
Exactly.
The prophecy said,
"A boy would lead the tribe."
(HOOK LAUGHS)
So what?
You don't care.
I do. Keep going.
Well, Blackbeard thinks
the prophecy is about me,
which means
my mum is from here,
which means the natives
might know where she is.
HOOK: Are you insane?
Those savages would just
as soon kill you as help you.
- Ever met one?
- HOOK: No!
And I don't plan to.
Well, they might be very nice.
I'm not afraid of 'em.
There's a fine line between
bravery and suicide, kid.
I'm off to go find the
Tribal Territory. Oh, goodbye!
SMEE: He won't last
an hour out there.
His problem. Not ours.
Thing is, if he was the chosen one...
If that prophecy is real,
trust me, he ain't it.
But if they thought he was...
They believed he was...
I bet they'd handsomely reward
anyone who brought him to them.
Well, they haven't got a ship.
Yeah, but they could get one.
Who's fought the pirates
more than the natives?
If anyone could find a way, it's them.
HOOK: Just remember,
when we find those
oh-so-sweet-natured locals,
true or not, you tell them
you're their savior.
Then, we'll go
our separate ways. Got it?
Why would you want to leave
a place like this?
Where will you go?
I don't know. Somewhere
I'm a little higher up
on the food chain,
for starters.
(GASPS)
What was that?
Somethin' a little higher up
on the food chain.
Oh.
Oh, that is pretty, Hook.
Do you see that?
We got pirates tryin'
to shoot us down with cannons.
Nearly falling a thousand feet
to our deaths.
Twice. Shipwrecked.
And you see
something like that
and you think to yourself,
"Oh, worth it."
PETER: Are you an orphan?
HOOK: My ma left me.
That count?
PETER: Well,
do you remember her?
I'm not wasting tears missing
someone who never missed me.
Maybe she does.
How can you know?
Do you really believe
your mum's here?
Well, she left me
a note saying...
Oh, well,
if she left you a note, sure.
Just 'cause yours
never loved you...
- (DISTANT SHRIEKING)
- HOOK: Stop.
(MUFFLED) ...doesn't mean
my mum never loved me.
Stop talking right now.
(SHRIEKING)
Did you hear that?
It was a deafening
nightmare shriek.
How can anyone
not have heard...
HOOK: Shh.
- (CROAKING)
- (ALL GASPS)
(SHRIEKING)
HOOK: That's a Neverbird.
- (SMEE WHIMPERS)
- (NEVERBIRD CAWING)
And so is that.
What're we gonna do?
We need a plan.
We need a plan!
- (SHRIEKING)
- HOOK: Run!
We'll lose them
in the mist! Go!
- Go!
- (PETER SCREAMING)
Run, Smee!
(SHRIEKING)
SMEE: Their faces are terrible,
but their feathers
are quite lovely.
Shut up and run!
Go!
(PANTING)
(WHOOPING)
Smee!
(SMEE SCREAMING)
(PANTING)
(TRIBAL DRUM PLAYING)
HOOK: Peter!
Hook? Is that you?
HOOK: Peter.
Hook, they've got Smee.
No.
Don't worry. Everything's
- gonna be all right!
- (SHRIEKING)
(BOTH SCREAMS)
(BREATHING RAPIDLY)
I knew we'd find the natives.
We're saved.
- (NEVERBIRD SCREECHES)
- (SMEE GROANS)
Please! I'm ready
to go home now, please.
Let me handle this.
Good fair lady.
We come in peace.
And with treasure.
May I proudly present to you...
(GRUNTS)
(TRIBAL MUSIC
PLAYING IN DISTANCE)
(NATIVES SINGING)
ALL: (CHANTING) Pan!
Pan!
Pan! Pan!
(YAWNING)
Pan!
(GROANS)
Smee!
- Smee!
- What?
What are they singing about?
Search me!
ALL: (CHANTING) Pan! Pan!
What's going on? What's "Pan"?
The Pan is
our tribe's bravest warrior.
It's our tradition
to grant you the chance to win
your freedom before
we kill you and your friends.
Kill? What do you mean, "kill"?
You are our sworn enemy.
You're pirates.
Pirates? We're not pirates. Hold on!
The kid is the one
you've been waiting for.
Listen!
Your chance to live,
your fiercest fighter
against ours. Our Pan.
You win, you live.
- You lose...
- I get the idea.
Huh?
Bye for now.
(MUSIC STOPS)
(YELLS)
(CROWD CHEERING)
(GRUNTS)
ALL: (CHANTING) Pan!
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- (HOOK LAUGHS MOCKINGLY)
So how do we know
when to start?
Whoa.
Whoa!
(GRUNTING)
- Whoa!
- (BREATHING HEAVILY)
(YELLS)
- (GROANS)
- Oh!
- Smee!
- What?
We have to tell them
about my mother.
No one cares
about your darn mother!
Sorry, that was a bit harsh.
(GROANS)
Ahh!
- (GROANS)
- (ALL GASPS)
(CHANTING CONTINUES)
Okay.
(GROWLS)
(GROANS)
Your Highness.
I was hoping to get you alone.
(YELLING)
Stop!
The little one.
He wears the Pan.
(PEOPLE GASPING)
(WEAKLY)
He's a boy that can fly.
I've seen it. It's terrific.
(GROANS)
TIGER LILY: We call this
the Memory Tree.
It was a time of war.
Blackbeard destroyed
everything in pursuit
of the Pixum.
But then,
the chief made a pact
with the great fairy king,
uniting our peoples
against the pirates.
One night, the king's son,
the fairy prince,
found his way
onto Blackbeard's ship.
Her name was Mary,
the love of Blackbeard's life
and his most prized
possession.
Night after night,
the prince visited Mary.
But when Blackbeard
discovered them,
he flew into a jealous rage.
So in order to save her,
the prince took human form.
But though fairies can live
many thousands of years,
in human flesh,
they can live only one day.
The prince sacrificed his life
for the girl he loved.
And the child of that love
was you.
Our people helped your mother
hide you in the other world.
And they made you this totem,
so that when you returned,
we would know it was you.
What happened to my mother?
She returned to the Neverwood
and fought for us many years.
And?
The pirates
were winning the war,
and the fairies had to retreat
to a hidden kingdom.
They've remained there, in hiding,
unknown by Blackbeard
until a time when they can
reemerge and fight.
And my mother?
- She's with them.
- She's alive?
Are you sure?
I have to go to her!
- Please, take me now!
- CHIEF: No.
You must be patient.
But she's waiting for me.
The fairy kingdom is the
greatest secret of this land.
Our duty is to protect it.
Before we take you there,
you must prove yourself
to be Mary's son.
The one we've been waiting for.
When the third moon rises,
he must fly.
(GULPS)
If he lives,
he's the one.
(SMEE CLEARS THROAT, WHISTLES)
One second.
And if he dies?
He's an imposter.
His death Will be justified.
Three days!
I've got the necklace.
Isn't that enough?
You could've stolen it.
But I didn't. Tell her!
Kid's always had that thing.
How long have you known him?
- Three days.
- All my life.
The flying thing
is a stupid detail.
Why can't they just see that?
If you don't believe, Peter,
then neither will they.
But if you do, they will, too.
I promise.
Are you who they think you are?
- I don't know.
- Hey.
They think
you're their messiah,
that you're here
to liberate them.
Are they right?
I said, I don't know!
(SNORING)
Rabbits.
(MUMBLING GIBBERISH)
(MUSIC PLAYING)
I believe.
I can fly!
If only Nibs was here.
He'd know how to help.
I believe.
(GROANS)
Have you seen Smee?
These things
they expect me to do,
I can't do them, Hook.
I've tried.
- Hey. Stop. Hey!
- I can't do the things,
so I can't be the one!
Listen.
Hook, what the bloody hell am I?
You can go feeling sorry for
yourself all you want, kid.
But knowing where you're from,
that's half of knowing
who you are.
That's more than most of us
here will ever know.
But you said
that your mother left you.
Yeah. I lied.
I do that sometimes.
It's called being a grown-up!
Least you know
where you come from.
Born to a warrior,
heir to a prince.
Does that mean you're the one?
I don't know.
I don't know
if there is a "one."
But I do know
that if you aren't the guy,
and you are just you,
maybe that's enough.
(GRUNTING)
(HUMMING)
- BLACKBEARD: Where's the boy?
- (GASPS)
Spill the beans,
or I'll spill your blood.
I'll never tell.
He's right over there.
Nope, nope. Wait, my mistake.
Pretty sure it's that way. No!
No. Right the first time.
Definitely, maybe definitely, this way.
The point is,
we're very close. (CHUCKLES)
Ready the ships.
Bishop, kill him.
No! Just wait!
Wait!
You might not wanna
kill me just yet.
For I hold the crown jewels,
you know.
- Informationally.
- BLACKBEARD: Speak.
Sorry, a bit nervous.
You are quite intimidating.
Speak!
Now, you know the so-called
extinct fairy kingdom, hmm?
Speak.
Sorry.
I was just lookin' for you.
Well, you found me.
HOOK: Don't see things
like that in the mines.
Kinda beautiful.
So, do you like sunrises?
(LAUGHS)
What is it you think
you're doing?
Well, I think
it's called flirting,
but if you have to ask,
I might be doin' it wrong.
You're not like the men
from my tribe.
Thank you.
No, they're honest.
Oh.
- Strong. Brave.
- Brave.
That what you call it?
Letting my little buddy
take a leap to his death.
When he ceases
to doubt himself, he will fly.
How do we know
there are any fairies
still left on this island
or that they'll come help fight
just 'cause they see him fly?
You have to trust us.
Why should we?
You certainly don't trust us.
There's a map
to the fairy kingdom.
We guard it with our lives.
Of course there is.
Why wouldn't there be a secret
map to the secret kingdom?
This isn't a game.
You've seen what Blackbeard
has done to Neverland already.
He'll reduce the rest of it
to nothing but mine pits
if we don't stop him.
Has anybody ever told you
you have really
beautiful eyes?
COMMANDING PIRATE:
Fire on the foredeck,
prepare to come around.
(PIRATES SHOUTING)
Tiger Lily!
You missed.
(GROANS)
(GASPS)
(GUNS FIRING)
(ALL SCREAMING)
Ha-ha!
(GASPS)
We must find Peter!
PIRATE: Shoot her!
- Peter!
- Where's Hook?
All of this because of you.
No, Kwahu, wait!
(GUNSHOTS)
You're welcome. Now, come on.
Keep moving!
(GUN CLICKING)
BLACKBEARD:
Well, well, well.
The princess, I presume.
HOOK: Oh, well, actually,
I'm just a miner,
but I appreciate
the compliment.
Bishop.
(GROANS)
Go on.
BISHOP: Line them up.
Down here.
(NEVERBIRD CAWING)
All these years
digging our hands raw
for tiny lumps of Pixum,
and now I learn from Mr. Smee
you know where there's
a mountain of the stuff.
(ALL LAUGHING)
Nice as pie.
Tell me where the boy is
and how to find the fairy
kingdom, and you may live.
Death is the greatest adventure.
Bon voyage.
(GUNSHOT)
(NEVERBIRDS CAWING)
All hail the new Chiefette.
Princess Tiger Lily.
PIRATES: (MOCKINGLY) All hail!
Tell him. He'll kill you.
He's right, you know.
(PANTING)
Nice birdie.
(SQUAWKING)
- There's a map.
- Traitor.
HOOK: Don't shoot her.
She told me there's a map
to the fairy kingdom.
Traitor! How dare
you betray us, pirate?
I'm trying to save
your lives, sweetheart.
It won't happen again.
Oh, it won't, I guarantee it.
BISHOP: Captain.
Go, kid.
(WHOOPING)
Yeah!
Kill them all!
Whoa!
BISHOP: Attack. Attack!
(WHOOPING)
(PETER SCREAMS)
No!
(SWORD CLANGING)
BLACKBEARD:
Can I tell you something, Peter?
You'll never find your mother.
Yes, I will find her.
No, you really, really won't.
You'll never find your mother.
Do you know why?
Because I killed her.
She died at my hand.
By this very blade.
- (GASPS)
- As you will, too.
Close your eyes, Peter,
and think a happy thought.
Bad form, sir!
We have to run, now!
No. We have to jump.
(GROANS)
(HOOK GROANS)
Peter, are you hurt?
Well, I'm fine, too.
Thanks for asking.
Don't speak to me.
Because of you, everything my
people have fought to protect
- will be destroyed.
- Hey...
Because of you,
the Chief is dead.
- Smee was the rat.
- He was your friend.
- How was I supposed to know?
- You should've known.
- I'm sorry.
I'm sorry if I did something wrong!
Where's Peter?
Peter.
PETER: You lied.
- You all lied.
- I'm sorry.
So, it's true?
It's complicated.
Is my mother alive
or isn't she?
Blackbeard spoke the truth.
And you lied to me.
Had we told you she was dead,
you'd have walked away
from your destiny.
Whoever it is you think I am,
whatever it is
you expect me to be,
I'm not.
And I can't.
(PETER SOBBING)
I couldn't...
I didn't wanna watch you die.
You should've
closed your eyes.
TIGER LILY: Blackbeard won't
stop searching for Peter.
There's only one place
on this island
he wouldn't dare look.
Mermaid Lagoon? Sounds pretty.
So pirates are afraid
of mermaids?
Because of what we will pass
through to get there.
HOOK: Yeah?
TIGER LILY: Crocodiles.
Afraid?
No, ma'am.
Find the map. Keep looking.
Does Smee please thee?
BISHOP: Pull the place apart!
- So may Smee be free?
- No, you're too useful.
But Smee was promised...
Smee should cease to talk of
himself in the third person,
- or Smee will be a non-person.
- Yes.
(SMEE GASPS)
I found it.
It's a map
to the fairy kingdom.
BLACKBEARD: Ready the ships!
We must get there
before Peter.
(SCREAMS)
Grab the torches.
They're afraid of the light.
Did we scare 'em off?
Oh, come on. They can fly?
Keep waving the torches.
There!
HOOK: Peter!
Peter!
I think I see him.
Where?
- Reach for my hand!
- PETER: (MUFFLED) Help! Help!
Peter.
What happened?
What the heck are those?
I don't know, but I think
you're gonna like 'em.
You could say that again.
Hey, hey, hey. Don't go.
- I'm gonna check it out.
- Be careful.
Who's more careful than me?
I'm sorry I didn't tell you
what happened to your mother.
But Blackbeard didn't tell you
the whole truth either.
Let me show you.
The mermaids charged
these waters with memories.
You can see the past.
Deep breath.
There's no time.
Blackbeard's men
nearly have us.
Go to the fairy kingdom. Hide.
Keep our people safe.
You should never have
come back, Mary.
And yet, here you are.
Ready to die for them
rather than live with me.
(MARY GROANS)
No. Mary.
No! No.
No!
(GASPS)
She was a warrior.
A great warrior. Her sacrifice
still inspires us.
Did you know her?
She trained me.
Would she have been
proud of me?
Yes.
Very.
But what if I can't do
what she did?
What if I fail
to fulfill the prophecy?
And what if you fail to try, Peter?
What are you then?
HOOK: Hey!
You've gotta see this.
Now, the hull's
a little banged up.
And see those teeth marks?
Boy, those crocs can jump.
But once I get her fixed up,
she's gonna be in good shape.
For what?
To get us the hell off this island.
You're going to run like a coward?
Well, I never really thought
of it in those exact terms,
but, generally speaking, yes.
And where will you go?
Home. It's, you know,
where I come from.
Home's not where you come from.
It's where you make it.
So help me do that.
Anyone that survived Blackbeard's attack
is in the mine by now.
And I've been there,
and I'm not going back.
Not for anything or anyone.
Well, if you have
no reason to stay, then go.
Go now. Leave us to die.
I don't want you to die.
I want you to come with me.
And if I don't?
Then that's your decision. Not mine.
Well, kid.
Looks like the old gang's back together.
Let's get this ship in the air.
Let's get one thing straight.
I'm not the chosen one,
and the prophecy wasn't about me
if it was ever real at all.
But I am my mother's son.
And if Blackbeard is going to destroy
everything my parents died for,
I'll stand against him to the last.
Just like they did.
Now,
take me to the fairy kingdom.
TIGER LILY: It's just as
the Chief described it.
These are words.
- What language is it?
- TIGER LILY: Must be fairy.
I can read.
I can read it.
What does it say?
"Only the prince
who bears the key shall pass."
Just that.
Then some boring stuff about
the great fallen dead.
It means we need a key.
Then this was all for nothing.
BLACKBEARD:
No, I wouldn't say that.
"The prince who bears the key."
Don't you see, Peter?
- I am the...
- BLACKBEARD: You bear the key.
I do?
You've had it all along.
- She knew I'd come for her.
- BLACKBEARD: Yes.
Mum tries to protect the kingdom
by giving son the key.
I kill Mum, but fail to kill the son.
In turn, son fails to protect the kingdom
by giving me the key.
Mum would be very disappointed.
Wouldn't she?
(SNIFFING)
Eternity beckons.
I will live forever.
Wakey, wakey! Rise and shine!
That's where we're going.
The fairy hive.
Destroy that, and we destroy them all.
Yes!
Yes! Oh! Come!
(BLACKBEARD LAUGHING)
Come on. Come.
Yes.
(FAIRY TINKLING)
PETER: Her name's Tinkerbell.
I can hear her.
They've been waiting for you, Peter.
(TINKERBELL SQUEAKING)
You have to get away from here!
He's going to destroy you all.
I know what I was meant to do,
but I failed.
I'm sorry.
I'm sorry!
All right, boys, let's burn them!
Burn them!
Bum them, burn them, burn them!
- Burn them all!
- No!
Please, I'll do anything!
- Please!
- Oh, don't beg.
Anything.
No. It's bad form to beg.
Where's your sense of honor, boy?
Now, kneel.
I said kneel!
I am the son of a warrior and a prince.
I will never bow to you.
If you're gonna kill me,
then get on with it.
As you wish.
You don't have to do this.
No.
But I really want to.
Did you miss me?
(CHUCKLES)
Why is it always him?
(GASPS)
Jump!
(SCREAMS)
You came back!
I thought you didn't care!
Like I said, sometimes I lie.
Come on!
I can't let Blackbeard get to the hive!
Hard to port!
Mind if I cut in?
(PIRATE SCREAMS)
(GRUNTS)
We've gotta help her!
Take the wheel!
You're gonna get this puppy
as close to them as you can.
- Okay!
- And I'll jump across!
Hold on!
(GRUNTING)
BISHOP: Captain!
(LAUGHING)
No.
Peter, no!
(YELLING)
(LAUGHING)
(SCREAMING)
(GROANING)
(PANTING)
No.
(STRAINING)
It's over, boy.
Come.
(BOTH GRUNTING)
You! Grab that girl!
Pan!
I can fly!
Look at me, Hook, I'm flying!
All right, you don't have to
crow about it.
Whoa!
Crow all you want!
Just don't drop me!
Go on.
(FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
If we're gonna beat him,
we're gonna do it together.
Do you hear me?
(FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
Good!
Now, come on, then.
BLACKBEARD: Fire!
(FAIRIES SQUEAKING)
PETER: Ready?
Go!
(PIRATE SCREAMING)
(PIRATES YELPING)
(SCREAMING)
(WHOOPING)
Got you!
Think a happy thought.
(SCREAMING)
BLACKBEARD: No!
Boy!
♪ Hello ♪
Peter.
Mum?
MARY: You found me.
I have your eyes.
You have my heart.
I've imagined this moment
my whole life, and now...
I love you, Mum. So much.
I don't know how you can miss
someone you've never met,
but I've missed you every day.
Every day?
Without you, I'm lost again.
What do I do now?
You're not lost.
You are home.
On this island, with these people.
Your people.
Your family.
You must never give up on them,
as you never gave up on me.
But, Mum,
I don't want to lose you again.
MARY: You'll never lose me.
I'll always be part of this Neverland.
And a part of you.
I love you, my son.
My Peter.
My Peter Pan.
(PEOPLE SHOUTING INDISTINCTLY)
(BOYS SNORING)
Peter.
Peter?
You thought I'd leave you here.
- No, I never.
- Feel like some fun?
Yes, please.
(SNORING LOUDLY)
(BREATHING HEAVILY)
(BOYS LAUGHING)
(ALL GASPING)
All right, gentlemen.
- Hold on tight.
- NIBS: Peter!
You don't have a rope.
We have a lot to talk about.
(ALL CHEERING)
(PETER LAUGHS)
(GROWLING)
I thought you were leaving.
Change of heart.
Will you take the wheel, please?
You don't want to go home?
I already am.
(CHUCKLES)
NIBS: Is he a pirate, too?
No.
Not yet, anyway.
Which way shall we go?
- Set a course!
Hey, who's in charge here?
Well, I'm the captain.
And I'm the chosen one.
We'll have plenty of time
to argue about that later, flyboy.
Suit yourself, Captain Hook.
Set a course.
Second to the right
and straight on till morning.
(ALL CHEERING)
BOY: Neverland!
Neverland!
PETER: We'll always
be friends, Hook. Won't we?
HOOK: Always.
What could possibly go wrong?
Improved By: Fidel33
Sub Upload Date: December 10, 2015